Guide to the Giles Yeomans Newton Papers, 1778-1986, undated
Giles Yeomans Newton papers 1778-1986, undated
Newton, Giles Yeomans, 1893-1987
Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Durham, North Carolina 27708-0185
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Biographical Note
Giles Yeomans Newton was a North Carolina politician and attorney.
Collection Overview
Chiefly diaries but also includes correspondence, other writings and speeches, printed material, memoranda, photocopies of clippings, financial and genealogical papers, and family photographs. The collection principally relates to Newton's career as a politician and attorney as described in his extensive diaries, 1907-1984. He ran unsuccessfully as a Democrat to the U.S. House of Representatives, 8th District, N.C. in 1938, 1940, and 1942. He also unsuccessfully ran for the Democratic nomination for the U.S. Senate in 1944.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
United States. Congress. Senate.
United States. Congress.
United States. Congress. House.
Democatic Party (U.S.).
United States. Congress -- Elections, 1938
United States. Congress -- Elections, 1940
United States. Congress -- Elections, 1942
United States. Congress -- Elections, 1944
North Carolina -- Politics and government.
Diaries
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series
  - 1918-1980, undated, (9 folders) (Box 1)
  - Jenkins, Ronnie B., 1976-1980, (2 folders)
  - Wiggins, Vera B., 1919-1934, (3 folders) (Box 2)
  - Memoranda, 1919-1936, (4 folders)
  - Memoranda, 1937-1960, (5 folders) (Box 35)
- Diaries Series
  - Diaries, 1907-1926, (5 folders) (Box 4)
  - Diaries, 1933, May-1942, Sept., (5 folders) (Box 5)
  - Diaries, 1948-1953, Aug., (5 folders) (Box 6)
  - Diaries, 1953, Sept.-1957, Aug., (5 folders) (Box 7)
  - Diaries, 1957, Sept.-1961, Sept., (5 folders) (Box 8)
  - Diaries, 1961, Oct.-1964, Nov., (43 folders) (Box 9)
  - Diaries, 1964, Dec.-1968, Sept., (5 folders) (Box 10)
  - Diaries, 1972, Sept.-1975, (5 folders) (Box 11)
  - Diaries, 1968, Oct.-1972, Aug., (5 folders) (Box 12)
  - Diaries, 1976-1979, Apr., (5 folders) (Box 13)
  - Diaries, 1979, May-1983, July, (5 folders) (Box 14)
  - Diaries, 1983, Aug.-1984, Oct., (3 folders) (Box 15)
- Miscellaneous Series
  - Printed Material, 1924-1979, undated
  - Writings, 1926-1974, undated, (5 folders) (Box 16)
  - Writings, My Political Book..., 1936, Mar. 8-1937, Jan. 28
  - Writings, Miscellaneous, 1916-1979, undated
  - Clippings, 1925-1947, undated (Box 17)
  - Financial papers, 1882-1947, undated
  - Genealogy, 1956-1986, undated
  - Pictures, 1889-1960s
  - General, 1778-1981, undated, (2 folders)
- Oversize Material
  - Miscellaneous Series
    - Clippings, 1925-1947, undated (Oversize-box 15)
    - General, 1778-1941, undated